[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这是一个非常简单的例子。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: That's a pretty simple example.
我们怎么可能有一个稍微复杂一点的问题呢？
How might we have a slightly more complex one?
这一次，我把CSP放在了所有事情的前面，因为
This one, I've got csp in front of everything because
我现在用的是图书馆。
I'm now using a library.
有用于CSP的库，其中一个库使用名称空间CSP。
There are libraries for CSP, and one of them uses the namespace csp for it.
你注意到我们把它叫做.go，因为我们模仿了围棋的惯例
And you notice that we call it .go because we're modeled off of that go routine
心态，来自围棋语言的东西，来自闭包脚本。
mentality, the stuff that comes from the GO language in from Closure script.
这就是我实际上如何将这两个生成器传递给可以做到这一点的东西。
So this is how I actually passed those two generators to something that can do it.
前面的代码片段只是假装有人做了，但是
The previous code snippet just pretended that somebody did it but
这是向前迈出的一小步。
this is a little bit further step along.
它向我们展示了它是如何工作的。
It shows us how it would work.
我们会将这些生成器传递给名为go和
We would pass those generators in to a method called Go and
你注意到现在我有一个真正的循环。
you notice now I have a while true loop going.
这会让那些东西永远运行。
Which is gonna let those things run forever.
这就是你最终如何建模这些独立的过程
That's how you end up modeling these independent processes that
运行您的应用程序，因为您最终基本上拥有它们中的每一个
run your application as you end up basically having every one of them with
一段时间真正的循环。
a while true loop in it.
它们都是独立运行的。
They're all running independently.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这里我从1号线到5号线，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So here I've got on line 1 through 5,
我在声明一个GO例程，每次有人让它
I'm declaring a go routine that's going to, every time somebody lets it
它将生成一个新的随机数并将其推入通道。
it's gonna generate a new random number and push it down the channel.
它想尽可能快地做到这一点，但如果你注意到这个概念
It would like to do that as fast as possible but if you'll notice the notion
这个阻塞通道是，它将会，这里有一个背压。
of this blocking channel is, it's going to be, there is a back pressure here.
它不会被允许以更快的速度向下推任何东西
It's not going to be allowed to push anything down the channel at any faster
速度比另一端的人正在消耗它，你能看到吗。
speed than somebody on the other end is consuming it, can you see that.
所以在通道的另一端，我有另一套完整的围棋程序
So on the other end of the channel, I have another go routine in an entirely
我的应用程序的不同部分，他每500毫秒等待一次。
different part of my application and he's waiting every 500 milliseconds.
他每隔500毫秒就会从通道中取出一些东西。
And he's pulling something off the channel once every 500 milliseconds.
听起来耳熟吗？
Does that sound familiar?
这听起来像是采样的溪流吗？
Does that sound like a sampled stream?
这是一种通过CSP语义对采样流进行建模的方法。
This is a way of modeling the sampled stream through CSP semantics.
所以3号线上的那个人是Note
So the guy up on line 3 is note
能够比某人消费的速度更快地推动随机值。
able to push the random values any faster than somebody is consuming.
而在第9行的人每500毫秒只消耗一次。
And the guy down on line 9 is consuming them only once every 500 milliseconds.
嗯，第9行的人不知道这些值是如何产生的，或者
Well, the guy in line 9 has no idea how those values are being produced or
他们来自哪里。
where they're coming from.
3号线上的人不知道是谁拿的。
The guy on line 3 has no idea who's taking them.
它们实际上是完全独立的顺序过程，但是
They're literally completely independent sequential processes but
它们能够通过阻塞通道语义进行协调。
they're able to coordinate through blocking channel semantics.
凯尔·辛普森：什么事？
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Yes?
&gt；&gt；演讲者2：这个应该多走一点，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: This should walking through this just a little bit more and
你现在可能正在做，但有两个镜头，对吧？
you might be doing it now but there's the two takes, right?
线上收益率-&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：第一个
Yield on line- &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: The first one
在第9行，是的。
on line 9, yep.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 2：第9行，即从第一个函数获取值？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Line 9, that is taking a value from the first function?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：但是看看它是从哪里开始的，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: But look where it's taking it from,
因为Take总是需要一个通道。
because take always requires a channel.
我们传递给它的是一个由timeout函数创建的通道。
And what we're passing to it is a channel that is created by the timeout function.
因此这个库提供的超时实用程序创建了
So the time out utility which is provided by this library creates
在500毫秒过去之前不会将消息向下推送的通道。
a channel that won't push a message down until after 500 milliseconds has passed.
所以我们基本上是说我想从那个频道
So we're basically saying I want to take from that channel and
我要等到那个频道给我点什么。
I'm gonna wait until that channel gives me something.
这是一种方式
That's a way for
我们来做阻塞语义或者我的意思是局部阻塞。
us to do the blocking semantics or I mean the blocking the local.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：也许我错过了什么频道？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Maybe I missed what is the channel?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：所以PUT和
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So the first argument to the put and
我们在这里展示的Take方法始终是一个通道。
the take methods that we're showing here is always a channel.
因此，如果我从由超时方法产生的通道中获取，
So if I take from a channel produced by the timeout method,
对我来说是什么频道都无关紧要，但是
it doesn't matter to me what channel it is, but
我知道那个频道在500毫秒后才会给我发信息。
I know that that channel is not gonna send me a message until after 500 milliseconds.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：上面有频道声明ch。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: There's a channel declaration ch above.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：是的，就像在上一张幻灯片中一样，我们在这里做了一个。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Yeah, it's like in the previous slide, we made one here.
这些库有不同的方式使您的渠道
These libraries have different ways of making your channel so
这就是你制作频道的方式，例如，在第一行。
that's how you make a channel is like up on line 1 for example.
在这里，我们只知道它存在于以太中。
Here that channel, we just know it exists in the ether.
它来自某个地方。&gt；&gt；扬声器3：渠道是善良的
It came from somewhere. &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Channel is kind
全球性的。
of a global though.
你说他们彼此不了解，但不知何故你必须拥有这个全球
You say they don't know about each other, but somehow you have to have this global
凯尔·辛普森(Kyle Simpson)：那是
state that's- &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: That's
在我看来，这个特殊图书馆的缺点之一。
in my opinion one of the downsides of this particular library.
它假定全局变量。
It assumes global variables.
我们会看到像我这样的其他图书馆不会这样做。
We'll see that other libraries like mine don't do that.
好吗？
okay?
但是，是的，这是一个细节，你必须想出某种方式来运输
But yes, that's a detail that you have to figure out some way to transport
使两个频道不同。
the channel so that the two different.
他们唯一需要知道的是他们必须共享一个引用
The only thing they have to know about is they have to share a reference to
频道。
the channel.
有很多不同的方法可以将全局变量作为
There's lots of different ways that you can do that global variables as
只是其中之一，好吗？
just one of them, okay?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：最后一件事我想给你们看，所以看跌和
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Last thing I wanna show you, so the puts and
拍摄相当直截了当，但是
takes are pretty straight forward but
实际上，这里定义了几十种不同的原语。
there are actually dozens of different primitives that are defined here.
PUT和Take是迄今为止最常用的。
Put and take are by far the most commonly used.
但是还有一个非常常用的，叫做alts。
But there's another one that's pretty commonly used, and it's called alts.
ALT允许您定义多个通道的列表，例如
Alts lets you define a list of multiple channels and say
我想在这些频道的第一个上做一些动作，让我做一些事情。
I want to do some action on the first of these channels that lets me do something.
所以你可能有两个频道你想从
So you might have two channels that you'd like to take from and
一个你想要播放的频道，你不关心这三个频道中的哪一个
one channel that you'd like to put on and you don't care which of those three
行动发生了，但你只是在等待某人解除你的封锁
actions happens but you're just waiting for somebody to unblocked you so
你可以做点什么。
that you can do something.
所以你在这里传递这些指令。
So you pass in those instructions here.
因为我只是传入了三个通道，默认的是我想从
Because I'm just passing in three channels the default is that I wanna take from
那些频道。
those channels.
但我也可以通过一个频道，我说我想放到这个频道。
But I could also pass in one channel where I'm saying I wanna put to this channel.
它不会到达2频道
And it's not gonna get to channel 2 and
如果通道1总是有一条消息准备好，则通道3。
channel 3 at all if channel 1 always has a message ready.
所以它基本上是说，为了我指定它们，不管是哪一个
So it's basically saying whichever one in order that I specify them whichever one
有一些东西给某人，有点像承诺的出品率。
has something for somebody it's kind of like a promised out rate sort of.
所以每个人都有东西给我，然后它会解开我，让我走。
So everyone has something for me, then it's gonna unblock me and let me go.
所以这是一种有很多不同的输入通道进来的方式
So this is a way to have lots of different input channels coming in and
能够管理所有这些不同的渠道。
being able to manage all of those different channels.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这只是我想说的一个愚蠢的例子，它是其中之一
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: That's just a silly example I wanted to throw in it's one of
在CSP的规范示例中，您会注意到，在第1行中，我创建了一个单次GO例程。
the canonical examples for CSP, you notice on line 1 I create a single go routine.
第二行就是我制作频道的地方，所以
And there on line 2 is where I'm making a channel so
您可以看到csp.chan，它使用这个特定库创建通道。
you see csp.chan that's on make a channel with this particular library.
所以我正在为我的频道制作一个乒乓球桌，并注意第4行和
So I'm making a ping pong table for my channel and notice lines 4 and
5正在创造更多的围棋例程。
5 are creating more go routines.
我调用go方法，并将它传递给另一个生成器的引用，
I'm calling the go method and I'm passing it a reference to another generator,
另一个GO程序，发电机在12号线上。
the another go routine, the generator that's on line 12.
所以我创建了两个我的Play or Go例程，所以
So I'm creating two instances of my play or go routine, so
现在我有三个围棋程序同时发生。
now I have three go routines happening at the same time.
我有一个主要的，它有点像这场比赛的裁判
I have this main one, which is kind of like the referee for the game and
然后我有两个球员。
then I have two players.
我有一张表代表我的频道，并且
And I have a table which represents my channel, and
我们交换信息的方式
the way we're going to trade information back and
FORTH是我们要在通道上来回交换一个球。
forth is that we're gonna trade a ball back and forth across the channels.
所以第一个玩家叫ping，第二个玩家叫pong。
So the first player is called ping in the second player is called pong.
你注意到第13行的玩家设置了一个while true循环。
And you notice that the player on line 13 it set up with a while true loop.
他说，虽然我可以继续，这基本上意味着永远。
He says while I can keep going which means basically forever.
我要从桌子上拿球，所以我在等球打到我身上。
I am going to take from the tables so I'm waiting for the ball to get hit to me.
只要我没有收到我的频道关闭的消息，
And as long as I didn't get the message that my channel is closed,
这告诉我游戏已经结束了，然后我要把我的点击数更新一，
which tells me that the game is over, then I'm going to update my hit count by one,
打印出我是那个击球的人这一事实。
print out the fact that I'm the one hitting the ball.
然后我会等待100毫秒来增加一点延迟
And then I'm gonna wait 100 milliseconds to add a little bit of latency to
系统，然后我要把球打回给另一个球员。
the system, and then I'm gonna hit the ball back to the other player.
这是第22行，我把球放回原处。
And that's line 22, and I put the ball back.
所以这两个不同的球员实例把球换回来
So these two different player instances that trade the ball back and
每100毫秒前进一次，直到裁判宣布比赛结束。
forth every 100 milliseconds until the referee says game over.
这就是在1000毫秒后第9行发生的情况
And that's what happens up on line 9 after 1000 milliseconds
裁判关闭了桌子频道，说比赛结束了。
the referee closes the table channel says the game's over.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：我第一次看到这个例子是在我有那个的时候，什么。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: First time I saw this example that's when I had that, what.
我以前从未见过这样的东西，从那以后我就被迷住了
I'd never seen anything like this before and ever since then I've been fascinated
并且积极研究我们如何才能做到这一点，并使我们的编程，我们
and actively researching how can we take that and make the programming that we
通过使事情更模块化和更容易理解，做得更合理，更容易理解
do more reasonable, more understandable by making things more modular and
更独立，所以我们的系统没有那么复杂。
more independent, so we don't have so much complexity in our systems.